<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recently on Ujjwal Nagar</title>
    <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/tags/recently/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recently on Ujjwal Nagar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ujjwal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/tags/recently/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/new_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/new_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by &lt;em&gt;Tom Macwright&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s recently posts series, maybe a lot of my ideas about website are inspired by him. I enjoy reading his blogs and his ideas about website, which has also shaped this website. If you find some similarities in design, formats of posts like this one, all credits go to him. Do read his blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://macwright.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was busy past 2 weeks building and tweaking the layout of this website. It turned out to be more challenging than I thought but I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made some progress. After going back and forth, reading Hugo&amp;rsquo;s docs, I think got the overall idea how it works. Still there are a lot of things to learn and I am still learning everytime it throws some novel error on my face.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Javascript is cool but it can be little hard to figure out on how to make it do what I want it to do. One of the biggest devil had become my friend now, it least in this scenario. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a lot of help from Copilot with GPT-5 model in it. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried it earlier with GPT-4.1 and some Claude models; that was a very frustrating experience. One issue here is that everytime I enter a prompt it feels like oh I&amp;rsquo;ve burned so much of planet to get this stupid code which doesn&amp;rsquo;t even run. GPT-5 works much better and gives you some useful thing. Although sometimes it is still frustrating to work with, especially when it hallucinates and, keep giving the same kind of output.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with LLM&amp;rsquo;s these days and will post seperately about my experiments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;watching&#34;&gt;Watching&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched two movies &lt;strong&gt;Contact (1997) and Geostorm (2017)&lt;/strong&gt; recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked the &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;; It felt like another Interstellar but made in 1997. Since it was made in the year 1997, you can imagine the effort they&amp;rsquo;ve put into the movie without all those cool VFX we have these days. I also liked the overall plot of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ellie, the protagonist, who is an astronomer working for SETI (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seti.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Real organisation&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;), looking for life out there. Facing all the challenges for her research funding, one day she find out some strange radio signals coming from space. It turned out that aliens are trying to contact us. When this news got out, the government took control of the project. When they were not able to understand the messages, she helped them out and keep the project going. Aliens send the blue print for a machine that will allow them to their star Vega. Then all the politics, religion, human desires cause chaos. It talks about religion, science and how we can live in this vast empty universe. I later realised that this movie is based on Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s Novel named same as movie &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; written in 1985.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did not liked the &lt;em&gt;Geostorm&lt;/em&gt; much because in the plot, things are put to the very extreme which I despise. I am leaned toward those movies in which story keep touch with some common sense. Although I love the underlying idea behind the movie about Geoenginerring, which is very relevant in present. Ideas about how Geoengineering projects can be weaponised is a really big concern will be one the biggest challenge if we were to ever try that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Geostorm&lt;/em&gt;, many countries have come together to build a weather controlling web of satellites surrounding the earth. It was headed by US. Just before they were about to hand it over to international community, things started to go wrong with system causing extreme events in some places of world. Two brothers one of which actually built the system and other one who works for the government tasked to figure out the problem. They race against time, finding the conspiracy behind the malfunctioning of system. If the system fails, it will cause a Geostorm, meaning extreme events around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie felt like hodgepodge and anything was happening with no sense behind it. I don&amp;rsquo;t like those kinds of movies where the protagonist need to survive at the cost of movie&amp;rsquo;s plot. One things which I would like to highlight, is the idea of Geoengineering. We&amp;rsquo;ve studied this idea in our 2nd semester and I literally gave a presentation about the same. It is proposed to be  one of the solution to our Climate Change problem but it can be dangerous especially when you don&amp;rsquo;t have a spare planet. This movie does depict some of those dangers but taken it to too extreme. Since it is a fictional, you can spare that. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about geo-engineering some other day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;reading&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am still stuck on the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ministry of future&amp;rdquo; by Kim Stanly Robinson&lt;/em&gt;, which is taking more time than anticipated. It is getting interesting since I&amp;rsquo;ve finished half of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have following on my lineup but can change:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1984 by George Orwell&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;ve read half it out, got stuck but it is still in my lineup.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Joy of X by Steven Strogatz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate Change by Jason and Edmond&lt;/em&gt; - Read like starting 40 pages thrice. I will try to finish it soon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten tired of those stupid laughing sounds that come of in people&amp;rsquo;s reels, I can say I hate it (I do not hate anything). I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen anyone laughing to those laughing sounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For our GIS course, we learned some really cool things, about map projections and cartography. I&amp;rsquo;ve used projections in QGIS earlier but never really knew how it works. We did cartography project as a group, which I really enjoyed. Below is our final map assigned area in our campus, that we made with hands. It feels good to make your first maps with your hands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/images/cartography_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cartography_map&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For distance measurement we used google earth; of course we were allowed since it was a short project. It helped me learn what really matters in a map-what to discard and what to preserve.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
