<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ujjwal Nagar</title>
    <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ujjwal Nagar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ujjwal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ujjwalishere.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>किताबें - गुलज़ार</title>
      <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/%E0%A4%97%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BC%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/%E0%A4%97%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BC%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%B0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been reading a book &amp;ldquo;Selected Poems by Gulzar&amp;rdquo; edited by Pavan K.Verma, check it out if you like hindi poetry. Sharing one of the masterpiece by gulzar here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;किताबें झाँकती हैं बंद आलमारी के शीशों से,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बड़ी हसरत से तकती हैं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;महीनों अब मुलाकातें नहीं होतीं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो शामें इन की सोहबत में कटा करती थीं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;अब अक्सर &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;गुज़र जाती हैं &amp;lsquo;कम्प्यूटर&amp;rsquo; के पदों पर.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बड़ी बेचैन रहती हैं किताबें &amp;hellip;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;इन्हें अब नींद में चलने की आदत हो गई है&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बड़ी हसरत से तकती हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो क़दरें वो सुनाती थीं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कि जिनके &amp;lsquo;सेल&amp;rsquo; कभी मरते नहीं थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वो क़दरें अब नज़र आतीं नहीं घर में,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो रिश्ते वो सुनाती थीं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वह सारे उधड़े-उधड़े हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कोई सफ़ा पलटता हूँ तो इक सिसकी निकलती है,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कई लफ़्ज़ों के मानी गिर पड़े हैं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बिना पत्तों के सूखे ठूँठ लगते हैं वो सब अल्फ़ाज़,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जिन पर अब कोई मानी नहीं उगते,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बहुत-सी इस्तलाहें हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो मिट्टी के सकोरों की तरह बिखरी पड़ी हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;गिलासों ने उन्हें मतरूक कर डाला.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ज़ुबान पर ज़ायका आता था जो सफ्हे पलटने का,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;अब ऊँगली &amp;lsquo;क्लिक&amp;rsquo; करने से बस इक,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;झपकी गुज़रती है,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बहुत कुछ तह-ब-तह खुलता चला जाता है परदे पर,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;किताबों से जो ज़ाती राब्ता था, कट गया है.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कभी सीने पे रख के लेट जाते थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कभी गोदी में लेते थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कभी घुटनों को अपने रिहल की सूरत बना कर.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;नीम-सजदे में पढ़ा करते थे, छूते थे जबीं से,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वो सारा इल्म तो मिलता रहेगा आइन्दा भी.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;मगर वो जो किताबों में मिला करते थे सूखे फूल,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;और महके हुए रुक्क़े,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;किताबें माँगने, गिरने, उठाने के बहाने रिश्ते बनते थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उनका क्या होगा ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वो शायद अब नहीं होंगे !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Flanders Fields by John McCrae</title>
      <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/flanders_fields_poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/flanders_fields_poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Flanders fields the poppies blow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Between the crosses, row on row,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;That mark our place; and in the sky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The larks, still bravely singing, fly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Scarce heard amid the guns below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are the Dead. Short days ago&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;We lived, felt dawn, saw sunset glow,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Loved and were loved, and now we lie,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;In Flanders fields.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take up our quarrel with the foe:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;To you from failing hands we throw&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The torch; be yours to hold it high.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;If ye break faith with us who die&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;We shall not sleep, though poppies grow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;In Flanders fields.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Vonnegut on absurdity of war</title>
      <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/slaughterhouse_five_bookreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/slaughterhouse_five_bookreview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ujjwalishere.github.io/kurt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I am writing this post on December 24, 2024, there are around 110 conflicts going on around the world as per &lt;a href=&#34;https://geneva-academy.ch/galleries/today-s-armed-conflicts&#34;&gt;Geneva Academy&lt;/a&gt;. This is not new; humans have always used violence to settle their disputes and disagreement but the kind of world we live in can be lethal for humanity. We have two major wars going on right now, the war in Ukraine and the Israel-Palestine conflict and then are many civil wars like one in Sudan which has claimed countless lives and inflicted endless suffering. Now we have our politician&amp;rsquo;s glorification of war from the politicians of all sides, I do not know if they are lying, or they truly believe that. I think it is time to pause for a second and think what are we doing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People before us has warned countless time but we seemed to be living in an age of ignorance. One of such great authors was Kurt Vonnegut, who himself served in World War 2, was taken as POW and held in an underground slaughterhouse when the city of Dresden was bombed to ground. He has written a lot of novels, short-stories, plays and non-fiction. In the last two weeks I happen to read one of his famous book which has quite an interesting name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Slaughterhouse-Five, or, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Crusade: A Duty-Dance with Death&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a fictional book where the main character &amp;ldquo;Billy Pilgrim&amp;rdquo; has been kidnapped by aliens to be shown into their museum. These aliens are the being of fifth dimension, which means they can look into the future and also in past, they can basically look at the whole time in a single moment. Their philosophy was whatever happened happened and whatever will happen will happen, we should not worry about it and cherish the moment. Because he was being taken by these aliens, now he can also look into the future and the past. Over the course of story, he keeps travelling to one time or the other and always knowing what is going to happen next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This novel is written in a satirical tone with a dark humour where Kurt describes the Allied bombing of the Dresden city and his experiences after that but combining it with fiction. This is surely a fictional novel, but I think it much more than reality. Kurt used a lot of satire to describe the horrors of the war and how decent people gets turned into murderers. This novel explains the greater tragedy of war which is the human suffering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing he emphasised in the book that the wars are childish, and the soldiers are like children who do not know what they are doing. In the story when character went to his friend&amp;rsquo;s home and he was writing a book on war, his friend&amp;rsquo;s wife got upset. He realized that it is because she does not want her children or any of his children to die in wars. He then promised that this will not be a book that glorify war and hence book got the name &amp;ldquo;The Children&amp;rsquo;s Crusade&amp;rdquo; meaning wars are childish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe that although its a fictional book, but it holds a lot of lessons for us and our leaders on what is the human cost of wars. This book really captures a human experience of war and still as relevant as was when he wrote it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, the bird says &amp;ldquo;Poo-tee-weet?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Internet</title>
      <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/hello_internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/posts/hello_internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ujjwalishere.github.io/images/flower.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;flower&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about it for quite a while and today I have decided to give it a try. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of conversation with one of my good friend Rishabh and he is the one to give me the final nudge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes! I am starting to write on the internet, you may call it a blog or whatever but for me it&amp;rsquo;s just a way to share ideas. This happened after a lot of debate with Rishabh, and I finally do agree that it is necessary to share ideas as he put it as emitting signals in the world of noise. I am more of a listening person and most of the time I do not have much to say. Problem is people talk a lot, and you need to be very careful to not miss the real part from all the noise. In midst of all of that, there is always very little time to say and even if you do want to say hardly anyone wants to listen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another problem is about opinions, we all have our own opinions, and every opinion matters even if you don&amp;rsquo;t agree with it but sometimes they are not welcomed. Here from time to time I will be sharing my opinions and thoughts on things, you do not have to necessarily agree with me, sometimes even I do not agree with my own. Although I will try my best but if my opinions do hurt anyone and are not at all acceptable, do point it out on my e-mail. Right now, I do not have any preplanned ideas what I am going to do here, you can take this as a place where I share. I am sure you will something worth reading here and hopefully It will contribute into something good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to 2025 and hope it will bring good days and joy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Ujjwal, currently an undergraduate student at Azim Premji University Bengaluru majoring in Environmental Science and Sustainability.&#xA;I can not say I am something or the other because I feel like i am not good at anything. Sometimes I code, write poetry, play volleyball, click some beautiful pictures, just explore some random topic like &amp;ldquo;Matrioshka brain or Ligo&amp;rdquo;. I like opening things up and looking up what inside them or repairing broken old things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I thrive on exploring real world challenges and solving them by things I learn in classroom. I try to learn new things and explore world without the presumption of achieving something from that knowledge. I think this is what me makes me human.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I hope this place will give you a little peek into my world and hopefully you will learn more about some new things.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you have any question or anything, just drop me an e-mail.&#xA;: &lt;strong&gt;ujjwalnagar{@}hotmail{.}com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/ujjwalnagar08/&#34;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://stackoverflow.com/users/28903257/ujjwal&#34;&gt;Stackoverflow&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ujjwalishere&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/user/ujjwalishere/&#34;&gt;Reddit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ujjwal-nagar-india/&#34;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://bsky.app/profile/ujjwalnagar.bsky.social&#34;&gt;Bluesky&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ujjwalishere.github.io/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
