<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ujjwal Nagar</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ujjwal Nagar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ujjwal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Vonnegut on absurdity of war</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts/blog_1-slaughterhouse-five-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/blog_1-slaughterhouse-five-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/kurt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I am writing this post on December 24, 2024, there are around 110 conflicts going on around the world as per &lt;a href=&#34;https://geneva-academy.ch/galleries/today-s-armed-conflicts&#34;&gt;Geneva Academy&lt;/a&gt;. This is not new; humans have always used violence to settle their disputes and disagreement but the kind of world we live in can be lethal for humanity. We have two major wars going on right now, the war in Ukraine and the Israel-Palestine conflict and then are many civil wars like one in Sudan which has claimed countless lives and inflicted endless suffering. Now we have our politician&amp;rsquo;s glorification of war from the politicians of all sides, I do not know if they are lying, or they truly believe that. I think it is time to pause for a second and think what are we doing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am Ujjwal, currently an undergraduate student at Azim Premji University Bengaluru majoring in Environmental Science and Sustainability.&#xA;I can not say I am something or the other because I feel like i am not good at anything. Sometimes I code, write poetry, play volleyball, click some beautiful pictures, just explore some random topic like &amp;ldquo;Matrioshka brain or Ligo&amp;rdquo;. I like opening things up and looking up what inside them or repairing broken old things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
