<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writings on Ujjwal Nagar</title>
    <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writings on Ujjwal Nagar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Ujjwal</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Earth is not round</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/12-earth-is-not-round/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/12-earth-is-not-round/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, somebody told me that the Earth is round. I was amazed, but it took me years to properly digest that idea—not just one or two years, but many years. Still, I am making sense of that idea today, but how can it be like a ball? It looks pretty flat to me. I used to climb my terrace, curious about finding the curvature of the earth, but to no avail. There are a lot of people who still believe that the earth is flat, and I don&amp;rsquo;t think that they are stupid, as some might assume them to be. I found this really cool website about something called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tfes.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Flat Earth Society&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;. I liked the questions people asked in the forum.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Apart from these interesting discussions, Earth really is not flat. Does that mean it is round, and if it is round, then is it perfectly round? From the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Timeline_of_first_images_of_Earth_from_space&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;pictures taken from space&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;, it seems perfectly round, right? It definitely looks perfectly spherical, and that is the case from all the pictures taken from space.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d6/AS08-16-2593_remastered.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image of the earth&#34;&gt; &amp;ldquo;By NASA - Public Domain, &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=115500813&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=115500813&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-shape-of-the-earth&#34;&gt;What is the shape of the Earth?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In reality, the earth is not round like a sphere; it is actually some weird shape, something called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geoid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Geoid&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;. It looks something like the image below; it is an exaggerated figure, but it does show that the earth is not exactly round; it is kind of like a lumpy sphere. I know that this is not what comes to mind when we imagine Earth. The thing is, figuring out the shape of the Earth is a more challenging task, which can not be just solved by taking pictures from afar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4a/Geoid_undulation_10k_scale.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image of the earth&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;By International Centre for Global Earth Models (ICGEM) - CC BY 4.0, &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=81462823&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://commons.wikimedia.org/w/index.php?curid=81462823&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The problem with the Earth is that it is not a fixed sphere; it is constantly changing its shape all the time, with the movements of tides, ocean waves, clouds, tectonic plates, etc. So, determining the exact shape is difficult, but you need to come up with a shape that is somewhat constant, at least most of the time. The field for studying the Earth&amp;rsquo;s shape is called Geodesy, and geodesists have been trying to measure the exact shape of the Earth to this day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the methods they use to measure the Earth&amp;rsquo;s shape is using its gravity.. It is a clever technique to figure out shape, since the mass of the Earth remains constant and does not change position in short lengths of time. This mass is unevenly distributed, so that gravity in different places is going to vary. If we can measure these variations and imagine the Earth as a sphere of water, the shape that water will eventually take is going to be the approximate shape, right? To simplify, it depends on how dense the Earth is under your feet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With modern satellites like &lt;a href=&#34;https://grace.jpl.nasa.gov/mission/grace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;GRACE&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://earth.esa.int/eogateway/missions/goce&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;GOCE&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;, we have measured the gravity along the surface of the earth, and the picture above is the most accurate geoid we have come up with till now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interesting Application of Gravimetric Data&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The gravimetric method has some very unique applications, one of which is that you can use gravitational observation to track changes in groundwater levels over the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MaxBOvQ2a_o?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are a few important observations here,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The Earth is bulged around the equator, squished on the poles. This means that you&amp;rsquo;ll have more weight on poles as compared to the equator because of the distance from the centre of the Earth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you try to fit this shape into some form of sphere, it closely resembles an oblate sphere, bulged around the equator; this bulge is a little below the equator, not exactly on the equator.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The gravitational constant is not $9.8 m/s^2$ all over the earth; it differs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are places on Earth that have very high gravitational anomalies, like the Indian Ocean, which shows very anomalous gravity.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But whether you want to consider the earth as a spheroid, ellipsoid, or geoid, it all depends on what you are trying to achieve. For navigational purposes, the geoid makes life difficult, so we use a spheroid; for our normal globe models, a sphere works fine. If you really want an accurate shape for weather modelling, tracking water resources, or studying the Earth, then a geoid is helpful.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you want to know more, then this video from Neil deGrasse Tyson is a good watch: &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/K_Pqa-I0Z5U?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For now, I can say that the earth is spherical enough to say that it is a sphere, rather than flat enough to say it otherwise.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-did-i-get-into-all-of-this&#34;&gt;How did I get into all of this?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the past semester, I have been doing a course in GIS. I&amp;rsquo;ve come across maps, projections, and datum earlier, but I only knew what to do in GIS software and had a broad idea of how these all work. Right now, I&amp;rsquo;m really curious about geodesy and have spent quite a lot of time on this. It is interesting to know how things work behind the scenes. I know I have just scratched the surface for now, but at least now I know what I do not know. Right now, I am spending a lot of time learning projections and GPS, about which I have come up with some cool things. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to share that as soon as I find time. This semester is the most interesting one; I am learning so many interesting new things that I don&amp;rsquo;t have time to write about them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/earth-round.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/earth-round.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/geoid.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://oceanservice.noaa.gov/facts/geoid.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://geodesy.noaa.gov/GEOID/index.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://geodesy.noaa.gov/GEOID/index.shtml&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recently</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/new_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/new_post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is inspired by &lt;em&gt;Tom Macwright&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s recently posts series, maybe a lot of my ideas about website are inspired by him. I enjoy reading his blogs and his ideas about website, which has also shaped this website. If you find some similarities in design, formats of posts like this one, all credits go to him. Do read his blog &lt;a href=&#34;https://macwright.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was busy past 2 weeks building and tweaking the layout of this website. It turned out to be more challenging than I thought but I&amp;rsquo;ve finally made some progress. After going back and forth, reading Hugo&amp;rsquo;s docs, I think got the overall idea how it works. Still there are a lot of things to learn and I am still learning everytime it throws some novel error on my face.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Javascript is cool but it can be little hard to figure out on how to make it do what I want it to do. One of the biggest devil had become my friend now, it least in this scenario. Lately I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking a lot of help from Copilot with GPT-5 model in it. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried it earlier with GPT-4.1 and some Claude models; that was a very frustrating experience. One issue here is that everytime I enter a prompt it feels like oh I&amp;rsquo;ve burned so much of planet to get this stupid code which doesn&amp;rsquo;t even run. GPT-5 works much better and gives you some useful thing. Although sometimes it is still frustrating to work with, especially when it hallucinates and, keep giving the same kind of output.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with LLM&amp;rsquo;s these days and will post seperately about my experiments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;watching&#34;&gt;Watching&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched two movies &lt;strong&gt;Contact (1997) and Geostorm (2017)&lt;/strong&gt; recently.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I liked the &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt;; It felt like another Interstellar but made in 1997. Since it was made in the year 1997, you can imagine the effort they&amp;rsquo;ve put into the movie without all those cool VFX we have these days. I also liked the overall plot of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ellie, the protagonist, who is an astronomer working for SETI (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seti.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Real organisation&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;), looking for life out there. Facing all the challenges for her research funding, one day she find out some strange radio signals coming from space. It turned out that aliens are trying to contact us. When this news got out, the government took control of the project. When they were not able to understand the messages, she helped them out and keep the project going. Aliens send the blue print for a machine that will allow them to their star Vega. Then all the politics, religion, human desires cause chaos. It talks about religion, science and how we can live in this vast empty universe. I later realised that this movie is based on Carl Sagan&amp;rsquo;s Novel named same as movie &lt;em&gt;Contact&lt;/em&gt; written in 1985.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I did not liked the &lt;em&gt;Geostorm&lt;/em&gt; much because in the plot, things are put to the very extreme which I despise. I am leaned toward those movies in which story keep touch with some common sense. Although I love the underlying idea behind the movie about Geoenginerring, which is very relevant in present. Ideas about how Geoengineering projects can be weaponised is a really big concern will be one the biggest challenge if we were to ever try that.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Geostorm&lt;/em&gt;, many countries have come together to build a weather controlling web of satellites surrounding the earth. It was headed by US. Just before they were about to hand it over to international community, things started to go wrong with system causing extreme events in some places of world. Two brothers one of which actually built the system and other one who works for the government tasked to figure out the problem. They race against time, finding the conspiracy behind the malfunctioning of system. If the system fails, it will cause a Geostorm, meaning extreme events around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The movie felt like hodgepodge and anything was happening with no sense behind it. I don&amp;rsquo;t like those kinds of movies where the protagonist need to survive at the cost of movie&amp;rsquo;s plot. One things which I would like to highlight, is the idea of Geoengineering. We&amp;rsquo;ve studied this idea in our 2nd semester and I literally gave a presentation about the same. It is proposed to be  one of the solution to our Climate Change problem but it can be dangerous especially when you don&amp;rsquo;t have a spare planet. This movie does depict some of those dangers but taken it to too extreme. Since it is a fictional, you can spare that. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about geo-engineering some other day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;reading&#34;&gt;Reading&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am still stuck on the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ministry of future&amp;rdquo; by Kim Stanly Robinson&lt;/em&gt;, which is taking more time than anticipated. It is getting interesting since I&amp;rsquo;ve finished half of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I have following on my lineup but can change:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;1984 by George Orwell&lt;/em&gt; - I&amp;rsquo;ve read half it out, got stuck but it is still in my lineup.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Joy of X by Steven Strogatz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Climate Change by Jason and Edmond&lt;/em&gt; - Read like starting 40 pages thrice. I will try to finish it soon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten tired of those stupid laughing sounds that come of in people&amp;rsquo;s reels, I can say I hate it (I do not hate anything). I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen anyone laughing to those laughing sounds.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For our GIS course, we learned some really cool things, about map projections and cartography. I&amp;rsquo;ve used projections in QGIS earlier but never really knew how it works. We did cartography project as a group, which I really enjoyed. Below is our final map assigned area in our campus, that we made with hands. It feels good to make your first maps with your hands.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/images/cartography_map.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;cartography_map&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For distance measurement we used google earth; of course we were allowed since it was a short project. It helped me learn what really matters in a map-what to discard and what to preserve.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monthly Tape Mix - June 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/11-monthly-tape-mix---june-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/11-monthly-tape-mix---june-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-nectarine-raag-bihag---shoonyam&#34;&gt;1 Nectarine (Raag Bihag) - Shoonyam&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/FYNJbS99cfc?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FYNJbS99cfc&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FYNJbS99cfc&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-rang---abi-sampa&#34;&gt;2 Rang - Abi Sampa&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/YNCQPp0UaHk?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YNCQPp0UaHk&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YNCQPp0UaHk&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-bangles---niraj-chag&#34;&gt;3 Bangles - Niraj Chag&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VPDSGDgcGpM?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VPDSGDgcGpM&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VPDSGDgcGpM&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-papa-mama-loca-pipa--the-minions&#34;&gt;4 Papa Mama Loca Pipa- The Minions&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/x4QmZjQnxQU?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4QmZjQnxQU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=x4QmZjQnxQU&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-wellerman-sea-shanty---nathan-evans&#34;&gt;5 Wellerman (Sea Shanty) - Nathan Evans&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/qP-7GNoDJ5c?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qP-7GNoDJ5c&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qP-7GNoDJ5c&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;6-will-you-love-me-tomorrow---the-shirelles&#34;&gt;6 Will You Love Me Tomorrow - The Shirelles&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Y2e8B2CmicQ?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y2e8B2CmicQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y2e8B2CmicQ&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;7-untitled---sergio-díaz-de-rojas&#34;&gt;7 Untitled - Sergio Díaz De Rojas&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cc7hgJhlOA4?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cc7hgJhlOA4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cc7hgJhlOA4&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;8-bum-bum-bole---shaan&#34;&gt;8 Bum Bum Bole - Shaan&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NJ1NIIdHhXs?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJ1NIIdHhXs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NJ1NIIdHhXs&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;9-purvayi---midival-punditz&#34;&gt;9 Purvayi - Midival Punditz&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/dipbEodKmbU?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dipbEodKmbU&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dipbEodKmbU&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;10-त-रज-क-रजदलर---bansi-jogi&#34;&gt;10 तू राजा की राजदुलारी - Bansi Jogi&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/bBPxdL3jWlY?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bBPxdL3jWlY&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bBPxdL3jWlY&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monthly Tape Mix - May 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/10-monthly-tape-mix---may-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/10-monthly-tape-mix---may-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-jalalo-bilalo---raahein-gharana&#34;&gt;1 Jalalo Bilalo - Raahein Gharana&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/jRr-RVqP-l0?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jRr-RVqP-l0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jRr-RVqP-l0&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-atlantis---seafret&#34;&gt;2 Atlantis - Seafret&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gVAy3IZiL0s?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVAy3IZiL0s&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gVAy3IZiL0s&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-forever-ever-after---palace&#34;&gt;3 Forever Ever After - Palace&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/b2FN06o4wC8?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b2FN06o4wC8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=b2FN06o4wC8&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-aaj-din-chadheya---rahat-fateh-ali-khan&#34;&gt;4 Aaj Din Chadheya - Rahat Fateh Ali Khan&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IImcBEHuDRI?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IImcBEHuDRI&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IImcBEHuDRI&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-past-lives---martin-arteta&#34;&gt;5 Past Lives - Martin Arteta&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QcUwYwLx2Xw?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QcUwYwLx2Xw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QcUwYwLx2Xw&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;6-7-years---lukas-graham&#34;&gt;6 7 Years - Lukas Graham&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/LHCob76kigA?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LHCob76kigA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LHCob76kigA&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;7-whore---mehro&#34;&gt;7 Whore - Mehro&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZO8jCmiWaz4?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZO8jCmiWaz4&amp;amp;rco=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZO8jCmiWaz4&amp;rco=1&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;8-heer---ar-rahman&#34;&gt;8 Heer - A.R Rahman&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aNcxgxHcGYg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aNcxgxHcGYg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aNcxgxHcGYg&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;9-tune-jo-na-kaha---mohit-chauhan&#34;&gt;9 Tune Jo Na Kaha - Mohit Chauhan&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/01HR1uP4kic?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=01HR1uP4kic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=01HR1uP4kic&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;10-if-we-have-each-other---alec-benjamin&#34;&gt;10 If We Have Each Other - Alec Benjamin&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;&#xA;      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tscMSXk_jaQ?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tscMSXk_jaQ&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tscMSXk_jaQ&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why looking at stars made Earth more important</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/09--why-looking-at-stars-made-earth-more-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/09--why-looking-at-stars-made-earth-more-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.nasa.gov/wp-content/uploads/static/history/alsj/a11/AS11-36-5333HR.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Earth View - Image by NASA&#34; &gt;&#xD;&#xA;  &lt;figcaption&gt;Image Courtesy: NASA- &#34;Earth View&#34; - Apollo 11 Image Library &lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was always fascinated by stars, planets, and the possible life out there. I still remember when I was a kid; my great-grandpa passed away, I was told by somebody that he had now become a star in the sky. Maybe it was my grandpa itself who implanted all these stories in me.&#xA;Now, every time I look at the sky, the same feeling comes along with every gaze I take. There is awe and fascination only. If you&amp;rsquo;ve never got the chance, just take a look &lt;a href=&#34;https://apod.nasa.gov/apod&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; every day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I do not think this is me only, I am sure there are a lot of people around the world who feel the same. We all want to know, where we came from. What are we doing here? And Is there anyone out there or are we alone? Questions like this will come to mind.&#xA;We all want to go out and look for answers to all these gigantic questions. This is what humans have been doing all along, we went on voyages and sailed around the world. This is how we have found new continents, new people, new things. But our journey has not yet ended yet and we are still looking for the answers to the same questions, but now our ambitions are much bigger. We want to look on, at new planets, and new galaxies that we have found, and answers to the same questions. I would vehemently support such enquiries and will also participate in such endeavours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;But there is one thing I have observed over the years and it also bothers me some time. This may be mine and mine opinion only and I may not be correct. In search of all these answers we have forgotten our home, &amp;ldquo;The Earth&amp;rdquo;. People want to move to Mars, terraform Venus etc., it&amp;rsquo;s like they want to escape from the problems we have here on Earth. With the advent of climate change, biodiversity loss, pollution and all these problems, we seem to be overwhelmed and as the natural human instinct, we may want to just flee. Ideas like colonising Mars are great but they are not going to solve our problems, that&amp;rsquo;s the reality and we need to face it. We are not going anywhere at least in the short run of some hundreds of years and even If we may have the means, the earth will always be our home. I would never want to leave our home and not to return one day.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ll present some arguments why leaving the earth is not possible but it is the most foolish idea one could have:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Earth is our home, we were born here, and our ancestors lived here, and died here. Even explorers don&amp;rsquo;t just trash out their homes and just leave to look for another place. We explorers, wander around the world, looking for new things but in the end, we return to our home and take care of it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There is so much to explore on Earth that may be outside of Earth. We have such vast oceans that we have barely explored, still to this day every single time researchers take a dip into deep oceans, we&lt;a href=&#34;https://oceancensus.org/publications/press-release-the-ocean-census-discovers-over-800-new-marine-species/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt; find new species&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA; that no one could have imagined.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As far as we know to this date, there is only one confirmed place where life exists, it&amp;rsquo;s our pale blue dot &amp;ldquo;The Earth&amp;rdquo;. Why are we looking out there for something when we are living surrounded by it? There are so many different kinds of life, our understanding of them has just barely scratched the surface. There are around 8.7 million species we have discovered to this date and one amazing part is that the estimates suggest that 80% of species are yet to be discovered.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; Taxonomic catalogues are still incomplete for well-known species, and researchers are still finding species so rare that as soon as they find them, they go extinct. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As of June 2024, only 26.1% of the global seafloor has been mapped, we still know so less about our waters, we may have mapped stars and galaxies but we still have a long way to go when it comes to oceans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mapping the seafloor is one thing, actually figuring out what life is there is another thing. Estimates show that there may be between 700,000 and 1 million species in the ocean. These are mostly animals and exclude most microorganisms, which are estimated to be in millions. This means that two-thirds of these are yet to be discovered and around 2000 new species are found and accepted every year.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We still don&amp;rsquo;t know how the earth&amp;rsquo;s core exactly works and researchers keep finding new things. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;Researchers recently found out that the earth&amp;rsquo;s core changes shape and its rate of rotation over decades and how researchers figure that out is more interesting.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We still don&amp;rsquo;t properly understand how the earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field works and how it stayed for billions of years. If you don&amp;rsquo;t care about the magnetic field then you should because, the theory says that life exists on Earth because has a magnetic field, otherwise we would have been some barren planet like Mars with no atmosphere and fried by the radiation from Earth. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another thing is the clouds, we all see them, and feel them but do we understand them, NO! Clouds are much complicated than we think and they give a very hard time to meteorologists who are trying to predict weather. Clouds and aerosols are one of the biggest sources of uncertainty in all weather and climate models. &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These are just some of the things from the top of my head, that fascinate and puzzle me about the earth. Understanding and solving problems on earth will not only save us but may open new doors of understanding about the universe. We do not need to go to Mars and figure out &amp;ldquo;Novel ways of dying&amp;rdquo; as Sabine said, we need to think and solve our problems here, which will open the doors for the whole universe. I would end with just one line,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;A good journey starts from home&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/news.2011.498#:~:text=There%20are%208.7%20million%20eukaryotic,of%20marine%20species%20remain%20undiscovered&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/news.2011.498#:~:text=There%20are%208.7%20million%20eukaryotic,of%20marine%20species%20remain%20undiscovered&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0960982214016182&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0960982214016182&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://oceanexplorer.noaa.gov/facts/explored.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://oceanexplorer.noaa.gov/facts/explored.html&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://scitechdaily.com/ai-powered-breakthroughs-illuminate-earths-core-mysteries/#:~:text=Despite%20this%20basic%20understanding%2C%20many%20details%20remain,iron%2C%20which%20could%20impact%20the%20geodynamo%20effect&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://scitechdaily.com/ai-powered-breakthroughs-illuminate-earths-core-mysteries/#:~:text=Despite%20this%20basic%20understanding%2C%20many%20details%20remain,iron%2C%20which%20could%20impact%20the%20geodynamo%20effect&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;.&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01642-2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-025-01642-2&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.mit.edu/2020/origins-earth-magnetic-field-mystery-0408&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://news.mit.edu/2020/origins-earth-magnetic-field-mystery-0408&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/nsr/article/12/5/nwaf082/8051343&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://academic.oup.com/nsr/article/12/5/nwaf082/8051343&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01460-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41561-024-01460-y&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monthly Tape Mix - April 2025</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/08-monthly-tape-mix---april-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/08-monthly-tape-mix---april-25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-wings---luca-firth&#34;&gt;1 Wings - Luca Firth&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/VwjtXACtePk?si=fb-VdwG910eaJ_kQ&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-teri-justajoo---kshitij-tarey&#34;&gt;2 Teri Justajoo - Kshitij Tarey&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OCJCGCdF23c?si=qYoerxvfojEOpqU_&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-chithi-na-koi-sandesh---lata-mageshkar&#34;&gt;3 Chithi Na Koi Sandesh - Lata Mageshkar&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/lTlbTrePICo?si=olqibIDknQMaQcSV&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-bhar-do-jholi---sabri-brothers&#34;&gt;4 Bhar do Jholi - Sabri Brothers&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/EdCJZfRaq58?si=BO_40T4QrhoLJN-1&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-aashiyan---pritam&#34;&gt;5 Aashiyan - Pritam&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/OuNGySNJjWg?si=i97Ydfy6XDRn8XdS&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;6-best-day-of-my-life---american-authors&#34;&gt;6 Best day of my life - American Authors&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Y66j_BUCBMY?si=vxSDv3livkWVLztn&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;7-only---ry-x&#34;&gt;7 Only - RY X&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/bbokXheXhxY?si=bF60Nn11dohG5kA7&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;8-bulleya---vishal-shekhar&#34;&gt;8 Bulleya - Vishal Shekhar&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/a9Hxkc9YxGE?si=WgQaWfsOoPqJvT91&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;9-fortnach---sabestian-plano&#34;&gt;9 Fortnach - Sabestian Plano&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/XPrp6FUdgAs?si=irWS_OU5SECVh0CM&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;10-meant-to-be---krista-marina&#34;&gt;10 Meant To Be - Krista Marina&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/d-0htNDIxhY?si=4jq_Sq3_b3zvFOxA&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Radio memories</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/07-my-radio-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/07-my-radio-memories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am fascinated with the radio, and I always was, although there are differing reason today and when I was a kid. I remember those old Ramsons radios which was like having an iPhone at that time. There were some brands I never figured out, but they also worked flawlessly, just a minor tradeoff in sound quality. I remember me figuring out the best place to figure out the best signal. Sometimes it used to work only if your body is in contact with the antenna, the second you remove your hand, it ruined your favorite song. I somehow figured out that if you rig the antenna of a radio with the TV antenna (&lt;em&gt;Yagi antenna-&lt;/em&gt; I did not know the name at that time) then it worked like a charm. All the channels that used to play modern songs like Red FM, Radio city etc.; frequencies were on my fingers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then over time as TV got more popular and then phones, smartphones took over, the radio got lost, until one day I found one catching dust. It was a Ramsons model, but the string that connects tuner to external tuning knob was broken but overall, it was in good shape. I opened it, half of the solders had come out and half the wires I broke in the process. It used to work on the big D size batteries which is almost impossible to come by, but I got the info about the voltage, and I knew I can manage with a phone’s battery if I manage to solder one.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/images/radio.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Image of Radio&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first challenge was to figure out which wire goes where and that proved to be the most daunting task. I figured out the transistor model and then after a lot of google searches and research I found the schematics of it. It took some time to figure out what each component of the board does. It took me a few days to tweak connections and play with solder then one day I actually made it work. It was all static, no sound, no music or anything. I totally forgot about the antenna, I took a aluminum wire and used it as an antenna; and here we are, my radio was working. I was able to tune to like 4-5 channels, at night I got few more. I was so happy and for few days I only listened to it, my mom was thinking I had gone mad, but people do not realize that satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although I did not manage to close it properly because the external tuner knob and the tuner inside had this complicated pully-spring kind of system and some parts of it were missing. Then I got busy with all the other stuff, and it again went catching dust somewhere. I had some plans to build my own radio from scratch someday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I recently got interested in radio again because I got tired of listening to the same kind of music. I realized that radio used to give you exposure to new and random music taste but now I am stuck in my own filter bubble. Whether I use Spotify, YouTube, whatever they are all same algorithms. It trapped me in my own music bubble, and I am tired of it. I wanted something new, something surprising and then I tuned to the radio.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently I am playing around with an app called &lt;a href=&#34;https://radio.garden/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;RadioGarden&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;, although I have used it before but I am again gone back to using it. You get a map of a lot of radio stations around the world as little-little dots and then you can just play around. I found it so cool, not only do you find something new, but you also get to know what people are listening to around the world.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I found this channel called &lt;em&gt;Ujala Radio&lt;/em&gt; which is an Amsterdam, and I am addicted to it (&lt;em&gt;not because it bear resemblance to my name&lt;/em&gt;). First, I was surprised by a Hindi channel in Amsterdam until I realized there are many around the world. I looked for places in US, Canada because I knew that a lot of Indians live there, and I found more. I like radio garden, although sometimes ads are annoying but If I had money, I might have paid for it as well, but it does not interrupt your music like Spotify does. It also has a very beautiful website as well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here are some of the channels I am listening to these days:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://radio.garden/listen/ujala/sCFHyXDN&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Ujala Radio&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;         &lt;em&gt;Amsterdam, Netherlands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://radio.garden/listen/radio-sbs/HASfWUI8&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Radio SBS&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;           &lt;em&gt;Utrecht, Netherlands&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://radio.garden/listen/sangeet-radio-fm-95-1/3UYywf2B&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Sangeet Radio&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;em&gt;Houston, US&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://radio.garden/listen/radio-zindagi-am-540/zDDJjS8Z&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Radio Zindagi&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;     &lt;em&gt;Edison, US&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://radio.garden/listen/radio-privet/AAtNsdFf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Radio Privet&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;em&gt;Nytva, Russia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is not just &lt;em&gt;RadioGarden&lt;/em&gt;; I am also playing with the local radio on my smartphone, but you need more patience for that because you can’t be moving around.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve finally got my own domain</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/06-i-got-my-own-domain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/06-i-got-my-own-domain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I was not particularly obsessed with my name, it’s just that I was curious about finding out how domain works. I have seen a lot of people doing their own thing on their website and I liked that idea. Your domain and website are something you own. I want to own my presence on the internet and here we are –&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com&#34;&gt;www.ujjwalnagar.com&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When I started, I thought it will be an easy task to buy a domain; Trust me it turned out to be more daunting than I thought. It took me almost two weeks, just to buy a domain. There are a ton of companies, we all have seen their constant stream of ads on YouTube&#xA;, websites etc. but if you start to investigate what they offer, you’ll get to know how murky this domain market is. You will find a lot of companies offering free domain, but when you see the checkout page, it says that you must buy for 3 years and the first year is free, scam it is “no?”.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yearly price and renewal price are the first thing to look for, how much is their renewal price? And if there are conditions for it. Some of them don’t even let you buy a single year plan, most of the time it is bundled with hosting plans.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Privacy is another thing to look for. Most of the registrars don’t even provide Whois redaction and privacy and these are two different things. If you don’t know, whois is basically a public directory which stores all the information related to domain.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of my friend recently bought a domain, I was curious, so I just did a whois lookup on his domain. All his personal information including his Name, Mobile number, Email address and his Address are publicly visible to anyone. I texted him about this, but he texted me back saying that he can’t remove it because that is a paid service, and he has to pay for it. This is common across most of the registrars, they will not tell you until you buy the domain and then you realize.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the same with SSL certificates. Most of these famous registrars sell SSL certificates as add on which can cost half the price of your domain itself. Same problem with this also, you will not realize until you buy the domain. Sometimes they will say free SSL buy there is always a little * attached to it. If you are asking yourself, why do I need a SSL certificate, I’ll explain it to you simply. Have you seen that screen in your browser when you are trying to load a website, and your browser warns you with scary screen that an attacker might hack your information.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/images/attacker.png&#34; alt=&#34;Error Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;That happens because your site does not have an SSL certificate, and browsers can’t verify if it is a legit website or some spam. This again costs money, yes there are some sites that provide free SSL, but they don’t work. Most of these issues are with those registrars that spend so much on ads.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing I did was to do Whois lookup on famous sites, which registrar they are using, then I did a lot of research on registrars on what they are offering, read a lot of reviews on reddit about different registrars. All this research led to Cloudflare; I was really surprised to know that you can buy domain from Cloudflare. I have used Cloudflare only for their DNS, but most people will remember Cloudflare for their “I am not robot” or website security verification banner that comes before you load a website. I found Cloudflare good, their documentation and everything was very clear and there was no colorful message to deceive you. Most of the domain costs around $10.5 which is cheap when you compare to other registrars and renewal is also constant for every successive year. Apart from this they also give you SSL and privacy redaction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All this seemed good but when I tried to purchase, I ran into payment issues. First it does not support Rupay card, only international cards are supported and PayPal. I’ve tried 4-5 credit, debit card everything nothing worked. I’ve raised a ticket no one replied. I asked in their community forum and on Discord server, one person replied but that was not helpful at all and then everyone stopped replying. After trying for 1 week every day, I decided to move on from Cloudflare. Later they emailed me all these issues are because of new RBI policies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Then I moved to Porkbun, they are the only second registrar I found that provides SSL and privacy. I tried to register through Porkbun but that also failed. So, they have this thing where you must scan your ID and take a selfie to get verified, it is all automated. It got rejected. I asked their support team they sent me another link to verify; again failed. I was really frustrated and at this point I wanted to drop my plan. This last time I wrote to them and Walla, they just directly approved my Id. After that it only took max 15 mins to purchase my domain. They use Stripe as their payment processor which works well and the funny part is Porkbun itself uses Cloudflare DNS. You also get email forwarding for your domain. So, my new email address will be:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@ujjwalnagar.com&#34;&gt;contact@ujjwalnagar.com&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I’ll later talk about how I point it to my website, how I am hosting it, CNAME records etc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting Monthly Tape Mix</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/05-starting-monthly-tape-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/05-starting-monthly-tape-mix/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I listen a lot of music, for me it is like having some sweet after the dinner; Can live without it but don&amp;rsquo;t want to live without it. My listening habits are quite diverse and is not constrained by anything. I have lot of carefully crafted playlist and I thought it will not do any good if I keep it to myself. So I have decided that I will be sharing 10 songs, music, tunes, beats, etc. every month starting today. I will try my best to be consistent in this endeavour as possibly as I can. I have decided this to give a title: &lt;em&gt;Monthly Tape Mix.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My main platform for music is Spotify but I hate Spotify and today I found another reason. I tried to embed my songs into this page but it shows only preview, it makes music tik-toki which I do not want. I remember earlier it was not like that, this is their new trick, I used to love Spotify but that love is a fading love now. I am sure a day will come when we part our ways. I&amp;rsquo;ll try my best dear reader to not cause you too much inconvenience but I do not own these music platform. Maybe I will make my own one day and it will be totally open source, for now bear with me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So,&#xA;Monthly Tape Mix: March 2025&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;1-white-noize---bonaparte&#34;&gt;1. White Noize - Bonaparte&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I never watched the video of this one, I used to enjoy the music and lyrics until today and this song is trying to say something. I do not endorse anything shown in the video at all.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/35fuzCokzRU?si=F3pamkI3d-OFlbaw&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;2-stand-by-me---ben-e-king&#34;&gt;2. Stand by Me - Ben E King&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Ni85wmDuNfc?si=1e91j1792ItE7JwH&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;3-sailor-song---gigi-perez&#34;&gt;3. Sailor Song - Gigi Perez&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/1lrFsXkT_rM?si=yMDYRw0ON9jNuNFd&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;4-main-shayar-to-nahi---shailendra-singh&#34;&gt;4. Main Shayar to Nahi - Shailendra Singh&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/pDAI7vfjHGo?si=C0ZieR4rpWqVxi0U&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;5-barcelona-boy---ghostly-kisses&#34;&gt;5. Barcelona Boy - Ghostly Kisses&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/_M7rqQ2qo2M?si=wkNd4HsKOXmgTcGt&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;6-doro---aasen-kha-langa&#34;&gt;6. Doro - Aasen Kha Langa&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/m-78smnbJ5c?si=DrfGfzKogfEBebP6&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;7-shor-gul---swanand-kirkire&#34;&gt;7. Shor Gul - Swanand Kirkire&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/-gAJ4YIXyVc?si=dneJE8bgOD-2CrmI&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;8-i-am-a-poor-wayfaring-stranger---jos-slovick&#34;&gt;8. I Am a Poor Wayfaring Stranger - Jos Slovick&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/LJA0JSH7wgY?si=xXfGVD6yR44JNvYn&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;9-thunder---ry-x&#34;&gt;9. Thunder - RY X&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Nx-bsD8DgZM?si=Sk3X7X9h45RCCBlP&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;10-tum-prem-ho---mohit-lalwani&#34;&gt;10. Tum Prem Ho - Mohit Lalwani&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/Feoea8FQTI0?si=TIwxXFXVTlBDn0mj&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video player&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hope you&amp;rsquo;ll like these songs, if you want to share something do write to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>किताबें - गुलज़ार</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/04-%E0%A4%97%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BC%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/04-%E0%A4%97%E0%A5%81%E0%A4%B2%E0%A4%9C%E0%A4%BC%E0%A4%BE%E0%A4%B0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have been reading a book &amp;ldquo;Selected Poems by Gulzar&amp;rdquo; edited by Pavan K.Verma, check it out if you like hindi poetry. Sharing one of the masterpiece by gulzar here.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;किताबें झाँकती हैं बंद आलमारी के शीशों से,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बड़ी हसरत से तकती हैं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;महीनों अब मुलाकातें नहीं होतीं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो शामें इन की सोहबत में कटा करती थीं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;अब अक्सर &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;गुज़र जाती हैं &amp;lsquo;कम्प्यूटर&amp;rsquo; के पदों पर.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बड़ी बेचैन रहती हैं किताबें &amp;hellip;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;इन्हें अब नींद में चलने की आदत हो गई है&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बड़ी हसरत से तकती हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो क़दरें वो सुनाती थीं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कि जिनके &amp;lsquo;सेल&amp;rsquo; कभी मरते नहीं थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वो क़दरें अब नज़र आतीं नहीं घर में,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो रिश्ते वो सुनाती थीं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वह सारे उधड़े-उधड़े हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कोई सफ़ा पलटता हूँ तो इक सिसकी निकलती है,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कई लफ़्ज़ों के मानी गिर पड़े हैं.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बिना पत्तों के सूखे ठूँठ लगते हैं वो सब अल्फ़ाज़,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जिन पर अब कोई मानी नहीं उगते,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बहुत-सी इस्तलाहें हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;जो मिट्टी के सकोरों की तरह बिखरी पड़ी हैं,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;गिलासों ने उन्हें मतरूक कर डाला.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;ज़ुबान पर ज़ायका आता था जो सफ्हे पलटने का,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;अब ऊँगली &amp;lsquo;क्लिक&amp;rsquo; करने से बस इक,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;झपकी गुज़रती है,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;बहुत कुछ तह-ब-तह खुलता चला जाता है परदे पर,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;किताबों से जो ज़ाती राब्ता था, कट गया है.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कभी सीने पे रख के लेट जाते थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कभी गोदी में लेते थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;कभी घुटनों को अपने रिहल की सूरत बना कर.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;नीम-सजदे में पढ़ा करते थे, छूते थे जबीं से,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वो सारा इल्म तो मिलता रहेगा आइन्दा भी.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;मगर वो जो किताबों में मिला करते थे सूखे फूल,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;और महके हुए रुक्क़े,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;किताबें माँगने, गिरने, उठाने के बहाने रिश्ते बनते थे,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;उनका क्या होगा ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;वो शायद अब नहीं होंगे !&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In Flanders Fields by John McCrae</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/03-flanders_fields_poetry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/03-flanders_fields_poetry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In Flanders fields the poppies blow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Between the crosses, row on row,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;That mark our place; and in the sky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The larks, still bravely singing, fly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Scarce heard amid the guns below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We are the Dead. Short days ago&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;We lived, felt dawn, saw sunset glow,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Loved and were loved, and now we lie,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;In Flanders fields.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Take up our quarrel with the foe:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;To you from failing hands we throw&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;The torch; be yours to hold it high.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;If ye break faith with us who die&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;We shall not sleep, though poppies grow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;In Flanders fields.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kurt Vonnegut on absurdity of war</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/02-slaughterhouse_five_bookreview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/02-slaughterhouse_five_bookreview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/images/kurt.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kurt Vonnegut&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I am writing this post on December 24, 2024, there are around 110 conflicts going on around the world as per &lt;a href=&#34;https://geneva-academy.ch/galleries/today-s-armed-conflicts&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener noreferrer&#34;&gt;Geneva Academy&lt;/a&gt;&#xD;&#xA;. This is not new; humans have always used violence to settle their disputes and disagreement but the kind of world we live in can be lethal for humanity. We have two major wars going on right now, the war in Ukraine and the Israel-Palestine conflict and then are many civil wars like one in Sudan which has claimed countless lives and inflicted endless suffering. Now we have our politician&amp;rsquo;s glorification of war from the politicians of all sides, I do not know if they are lying, or they truly believe that. I think it is time to pause for a second and think what are we doing.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People before us has warned countless time but we seemed to be living in an age of ignorance. One of such great authors was Kurt Vonnegut, who himself served in World War 2, was taken as POW and held in an underground slaughterhouse when the city of Dresden was bombed to ground. He has written a lot of novels, short-stories, plays and non-fiction. In the last two weeks I happen to read one of his famous book which has quite an interesting name.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Slaughterhouse-Five, or, The Children&amp;rsquo;s Crusade: A Duty-Dance with Death&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is a fictional book where the main character &amp;ldquo;Billy Pilgrim&amp;rdquo; has been kidnapped by aliens to be shown into their museum. These aliens are the being of fifth dimension, which means they can look into the future and also in past, they can basically look at the whole time in a single moment. Their philosophy was whatever happened happened and whatever will happen will happen, we should not worry about it and cherish the moment. Because he was being taken by these aliens, now he can also look into the future and the past. Over the course of story, he keeps travelling to one time or the other and always knowing what is going to happen next.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This novel is written in a satirical tone with a dark humour where Kurt describes the Allied bombing of the Dresden city and his experiences after that but combining it with fiction. This is surely a fictional novel, but I think it much more than reality. Kurt used a lot of satire to describe the horrors of the war and how decent people gets turned into murderers. This novel explains the greater tragedy of war which is the human suffering.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One thing he emphasised in the book that the wars are childish, and the soldiers are like children who do not know what they are doing. In the story when character went to his friend&amp;rsquo;s home and he was writing a book on war, his friend&amp;rsquo;s wife got upset. He realized that it is because she does not want her children or any of his children to die in wars. He then promised that this will not be a book that glorify war and hence book got the name &amp;ldquo;The Children&amp;rsquo;s Crusade&amp;rdquo; meaning wars are childish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe that although its a fictional book, but it holds a lot of lessons for us and our leaders on what is the human cost of wars. This book really captures a human experience of war and still as relevant as was when he wrote it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So, the bird says &amp;ldquo;Poo-tee-weet?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello, Internet</title>
      <link>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/01-hello_internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/writings/01-hello_internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ujjwalnagar.com/images/flower.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;flower&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about it for quite a while and today I have decided to give it a try. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of conversation with one of my good friend Rishabh and he is the one to give me the final nudge.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yes! I am starting to write on the internet, you may call it a blog or whatever but for me it&amp;rsquo;s just a way to share ideas. This happened after a lot of debate with Rishabh, and I finally do agree that it is necessary to share ideas as he put it as emitting signals in the world of noise. I am more of a listening person and most of the time I do not have much to say. Problem is people talk a lot, and you need to be very careful to not miss the real part from all the noise. In midst of all of that, there is always very little time to say and even if you do want to say hardly anyone wants to listen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Another problem is about opinions, we all have our own opinions, and every opinion matters even if you don&amp;rsquo;t agree with it but sometimes they are not welcomed. Here from time to time I will be sharing my opinions and thoughts on things, you do not have to necessarily agree with me, sometimes even I do not agree with my own. Although I will try my best but if my opinions do hurt anyone and are not at all acceptable, do point it out on my e-mail. Right now, I do not have any preplanned ideas what I am going to do here, you can take this as a place where I share. I am sure you will something worth reading here and hopefully It will contribute into something good.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to 2025 and hope it will bring good days and joy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
